Emilio Balda



me@emilio-balda.com



linkedin.com/in/emiliobalda



+49 176 2803 7698



https://emilio-balda.com

Summary

I'm a full-stack developer with a Ph.D. in machine learning, passionate about data science in complex interconnected systems. Solid mathematical and programming skills. 5+ years of experience building software and working on research projects with publications at well-known conferences and journals.

Currently building No-Code Software with aiXbrain to empower medium-sized businesses to benefit from the latest machine learning technology.

Main skills: Python, TensorFlow, FastAPI, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Typescript, and Vue.js.

Specialties: Machine Learning, Statistics, and Signal Processing.

Experience

Full Stack Developer

aiXbrain GmbH

Nov 2019 - Present (3 years 5 months)

I develop machine learning SaaS for industrial planning and scheduling problems.

PHD Student

RWTH Aachen University

Feb 2017 - Oct 2019 (2 years 9 months)

I worked as a Researcher PhD Candidate in the area of deep learning, with a focus on the generation and theoretical understanding of adversarial examples.

Research Assistant

Fraunhofer IIS

Jul 2015 - Nov 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Analyzed, classified and modeled the statistical behavior of the motion profiles for antennas mounted on various vehicles and landscapes.

Education

RWTH Aachen University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Machine Learning 2017 - 2019

Technische Universität Ilmenau

Master's degree on Science of Communications and Signal Processing, Signal Processing and Communications



University of Navarra

Bachelor's degree in Telecommunication Systems Engineering, Telecommunications Engineering

2010 - 2014

Skills

Tailwind CSS • SQLAlchemy • Helm Charts • FastAPI • Vue.js • JavaScript • Gitlab • Machine Learning • Python • TensorFlow

Honors & Awards



Winner of the South American Youth Bridge Tournament - Confederación

Sudamericana de Bridge

May 2008

Our team won the 1st place in the Contract Bridge South American Championship that took place in Córdova-Argentina 2008 on the age category "Under 21"



Winner of the Ecuadorian National Bridge Tournament - Federación Ecuatoriana de Bridge

May 2010

Our team won the 1st place in the Contract Bridge National Championship of Ecuador 2010 on the age category "Open for everybody"



Best student paper award - Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems and

Computers

Oct 2018

Won the first place for the paper "On Generation of Adversarial Examples Using Convex Programming", co-authored by Arash Behboodi and Rudolf Mathar.



Finalist of the Körber-Stiftung Study Award - Körber-Stiftung

Jun 2020

I was one of the 11 finalists for the award of Ph.D. Thesis with the most social impact.